Sabin Kumar Thapa

Fredericton, NB | +1(506)-230-7876 | <u>sabinkumarthapa@gmail.com</u> | https://github.com/Sabinkthapa | www.linkedin.com/in/sabin-thapa-42715892

SUMMARY

I am a Front -end web developer, with a strong background and experiences of business management, added by ability to comprehend user behavior, preferences and business objectives while providing technical solution to the web application. My strengths includes teamwork, creativity and problem-Solving.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, Express, Node, Handlebars, Bootstrap

PROJECTS

Weather-App | https://github.com/Sabinkthapa/Weather-App.git | https://sabinkthapa.github.io/Weather-App/

- Summary: The weather apps display the current and next 5 days of weather details when user search based on the city
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GitHub, Heroku

Workforce-Explorer | https://github.com/Sabinkthapa/WorkForce-Explorer.git |

- Summary: The weather apps display the current and next 5 days of weather details when user search based on the city
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: NodeJS, MySQL

Simply-Notes | https://github.com/Sabinkthapa/SIMPLY-NOTES.git | simply-notetaker-fd25a61d938e.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: The weather apps display the current and next 5 days of weather details when user search based on the city
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: Express, JavaScript

EXPERIENCE

UPS | Brokerage rater

900 Hanwell Rd, Fredericton | 09.2022-Present

- Assesses duties, taxes and brokerage fees of imported commodities
- Ensures assessment of taxes and duties adhere to customs and revenue agency regulation
- Additional Support to OCR team, assisting rater in big shipments
- Making sure the shipment is rated within the cut-off time and also working in special shipment following the guidelines by shipper.

Edu Prime Global Pvt Ltd | Senior Counsellor

Dilli bazar, Kathmandu | **06.2020-07.2022**

 conduct informative sessions with students and parents to provide comprehensive advice on choosing the country, program of study, individual career goals and financial management includes student loans from financial institutions

- Assist students in building effective resumes and crafting statements of Purpose (SOPs) for their applications.
- Review and verify all necessary documents for student applications, ensuring completeness and accuracy.
- Create and maintain a workflow database in Excel to track each student's progress and application status. Ensure that important milestones and deadlines are met throughout the application process.

Samiksha Impex Pvt Ltd | Accounting/Finance Manager

Mahalaxmi-01, Lalitpur | 06.2017-05.2020

- Monitor the entry of bookkeeping transaction in accounting software (FINPRO), ensuring accuracy and compliance to accounting principles, identify any discrepancies or error in financial records and also rectify unadjusted entries
- Perform quarterly reporting and analysis of key financial ratios, such as debt equity ratios, interest coverage ratios, return on equity, and working capital ratios and present this analysis to management to assist in decision making and financial planning.
- Monitor and manage the company's cash flow to ensure it meets operational needs and financial obligations
- Manage financial aspects of vendor and supplier relationships, including negotiations and payment terms
- Review of gross margin, sales turnover based on region, clients, product category, inventory analysis based on reorder point, stock turnover rate

Samiksha Impex Pvt Ltd | Business Development Officer

Mahalaxmi-01, Lalitpur | 03.2015-04.2017

- Conduct a meticulous analysis of the market landscape in order to identify unexplored opportunities and gaps that align with our strengths as a team.
- Engage with sales team to be well-informed and responsive to market demands, deeper insights into
 pricing dynamics, dealer preferences and collecting invaluable feedback on our products and services
- Cultivate strong relationships with existing clients and nurturing these relationships, to not only enhance customer loyalty but also open doors to potential referrals from satisfied clients.
- Perform KPIs tied to revenue growth, profit margins, and revenue generated from specific client segments and track the benchmarks and guideposts in tracking our success.

EDUCATION

University of New Brunswick | Full stack Web Development

Fredericton, NB, Canada | 07-2023 - Present

Ace Institute of Management | Master of Business Administration

Kathmandu, Nepal | 08.2012-06.2015

Little Angles' College of Management | Bachelors of Business Information system Kathmandu, Nepal | 08.2006-06.2010